{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Human insulin formed by recombinant DNA technology is known as", "opta": "H insulin", "optb": "R insulin", "optc": "humulin", "optd": "huinsulin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The gene coding for VP1 is cloned in", "opta": "pMB 9", "optb": "pBR 322", "optc": "pUC 18", "optd": "pUC 19", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many nucleotides are there in Ss RNA molecule of picorna virus causing FMD?", "opta": "1000", "optb": "5000", "optc": "8000", "optd": "10000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recombinant vaccine for Hepatitis B virus has been synthesized against which of the following antigen?", "opta": "Viral core antigen (HBcAg)", "optb": "Viral surface antigen (HBsAg)", "optc": "e antigen (HBeAg)", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemically synthesized DNA sequences for the two chains are separately inserted into the plasmid pBR 322 by the side of", "opta": "\u03b2-Galactosidase", "optb": "galactokinase", "optc": "acid phosphatase", "optd": "glucokinase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Human growth hormone (hGH) is secreted by", "opta": "pitutary gland", "optb": "hypothalamus", "optc": "pancreas", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The promoter used for cloning HBV surface antigen is", "opta": "galactokinase", "optb": "alcohol dehydrogenase 1", "optc": "\u03b2-galactosidase", "optd": "polyhedrin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recombinant vaccine for HBV was produced by cloning viral genes in", "opta": "plasmids", "optb": "cosmids", "optc": "autonomously replicating plasmid of yeast", "optd": "phagemids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first therapeutic product formed by means of recombinant DNA technology is", "opta": "human growth hormone", "optb": "insulin", "optc": "hepatitis B vaccine", "optd": "vaccine for foot and mouth disease", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following capsid protein of picorna virus is immunogenic in nature?", "opta": "VP1", "optb": "VP2", "optc": "VP3", "optd": "VP4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two chains are joined together to constitute native insulin using", "opta": "sodium dissulphonate and sodium sulphite", "optb": "sodium dissulphonate and sodium sulphate", "optc": "sodium sulphate and sodium sulphite", "optd": "sodium sulphate only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Foot and mouth disease (FMD) of animals is caused by", "opta": "RNA virus", "optb": "DNA virus", "optc": "bacteria", "optd": "protozoa", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In India first genetically engineered vaccine against HBV was developed by", "opta": "Ranbaxy Pvt Ltd", "optb": "Shantha Biotechnics Pvt Ltd", "optc": "Dabur Pvt Ltd", "optd": "Glaxo Pvt Ltd", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The recombinant hGH lacks", "opta": "terminal glutamine", "optb": "terminal lysine", "optc": "terminal methionine", "optd": "terminal arginine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is human insulin synthesized using recombinant DNA technology?", "opta": "By using chemically synthesized DNA sequences for the two chains separately", "optb": "By isolating DNA from the islets of Langerhans of pancreas", "optc": "By using cDNA for insulin", "optd": "By using chemically synthesized DNA sequences for the complete insulin protein", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The two chains of insulin can be separated by detaching it from \u03b2-galactosidase using", "opta": "hydrogen chloride", "optb": "cyanogen bromide", "optc": "peptidase", "optd": "protease", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}